<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tools on Will Schenk</title><link>https://willschenk.com/tags/tools/</link><description>Recent content in tools on Will Schenk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/tools/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Askgit</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/using_askgit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/using_askgit/</guid><description>askgit provides a sql interface to your git repository. Let&amp;#39;s install it and see what we can figure out about the repo. Installing Following the instructions on the website, we can build the go binary with: go get -v -tags=sqlite_vtable github.com/augmentable-dev/askgit This will download the package, the dependencies, and compile everything into an executable. If you can&amp;#39;t figure out where it&amp;#39;s installed, check that you have GOPATH set correctly, and it will end up in $GOPATH/bin.</description></item><item><title>Building a hugo site and theme with Bootstrap</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2018/building-a-hugo-site/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2018/building-a-hugo-site/</guid><description>Now that&amp;rsquo;s its 2018 its time to retool the blog using hugo. Why not? Hugo is built in golang and is blazing fast and everything is cleaner than it was in the middleman years.
One of the reasons that I liked middleman &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s usage of the rails&amp;rsquo; Sprockets library &amp;ndash; is no longer a strength. The javascript and front-end world has moved over to WebPack and I&amp;rsquo;ve personally moved over to create-react-app.</description></item><item><title>Using rake for dataflow programming and data science</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/using-rake-for-dataflow-programming-and-data-science/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/using-rake-for-dataflow-programming-and-data-science/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Rake more and more for data collection and processing tasks. Rake is pretty pretty powerful. Most people know it as way to add external tasks to a Rails app, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually very powerful build system. We&amp;rsquo;re going to take advantage of that to build out a framework that will make it easy to collect, process, and interpret data while keeping it all in sync.
In fact, if you just want to start playing with stuff now, head over to the rake-data site to go through some walk throughs.</description></item><item><title>Middleman Tricks and Hacks</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/middleman-tricks-and-hacks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/middleman-tricks-and-hacks/</guid><description>As part of the process of getting this site to work, I learned some more things about how to better build a site with middleman. Building off of our foundational article here are a few other things that I found very useful when using middleman to build a static site with a bunch of dynamically generated content.
Partials The index.html.haml, articles.html.haml, tag.html.haml and calendar.html.haml pages all use the same partial to list out the post archives, which are mostly the same.</description></item><item><title>New HappySeed released</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/new-happyseed-released/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/new-happyseed-released/</guid><description>Make apps faster Head on over to the HappySeed website to get the latest version of HappyFunCorp&amp;rsquo;s starter application toolkit.
HappySeed is a set of application templates to help you get started building out new sites. The main section is a rails application template plus a set of rails generators to help you get started with rails appliations quickly. These generators setup the configuration of the application in a standard way, and the full set of generators include many things for setting up a modern rails app and well as middleman apps.</description></item><item><title>Building Sites with Middleman</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/building-sites-with-middleman/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/building-sites-with-middleman/</guid><description>I make a lot of websites, and I have a certain toolkit that I use to build them. The most useful things I use are:
layouts and partials so I only need to set things up once haml for writing html, since I don&amp;rsquo;t like closing tags Bootstrap and sass for writing css Markdown for formatting large blogs of content coffeescript for JavaScript Middleman is a static site generator, which means that it takes a bunch of source files, does some stuff with it, and produces static HTML, CSS, Images, and Javascript that can be hosted on a basic server somewhere, including hosting on S3 or Github Pages so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to consider a server.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrap: Advanced Grid Tricks</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/bootstrap-advanced-grid-tricks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/bootstrap-advanced-grid-tricks/</guid><description>We are a big fan of Bootstrap here at HappyFunCorp. While there are some arguments to be made if Bootstrap in particular is all that, or if Foundation is better for a given thing, its clear that starting with some sort of CSS framework is smarter than trying to roll everything yourself. [1]
There are three major complaints with using bootstrap.
All of the sites look the same. There are so many classes in the HTML where they don&amp;rsquo;t strictly belong It&amp;rsquo;s a whole bunch of stuff that you don&amp;rsquo;t need.</description></item></channel></rss>