<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>redis on Will Schenk</title><link>https://willschenk.com/tags/redis/</link><description>Recent content in redis on Will Schenk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/redis/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up redis and nat-connector with FaasD</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2021/setting_up_services_with_faasd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2021/setting_up_services_with_faasd/</guid><description>Lets look at how we expand our faasd server to include a couple of services. We&amp;#39;ll first add a redis server and some simple ruby code to add a counter, and then we&amp;#39;ll build and add the nats-connector to be able publish and subscribe to events. About /var/lib/faasd/docker-compose.yaml This looks like a docker-compose file, and I believe that it actually does use the same code that parses the file of that name, but it doesn&amp;#39;t use docker to set up the containers.</description></item><item><title>How to track your coworkers</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/how-to-track-your-coworkers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/how-to-track-your-coworkers/</guid><description>How much information do you bleed?
Ever wonder who is else is using your network? Or,who has actually showed up at the office?
Networking primer The simplest thing we can do to make this work is to check to see which devices have registered themselves on the network. As devices come and go, they connect automatically, so we will have a pretty good idea if people are there or not. Phones seem to attach and detach quite frequency, probably to conserve battery, so if we are want to answer the question &amp;ldquo;is so-and-so in the office&amp;rdquo; we&amp;rsquo;ll need to add additional logic to determine how far spaced the &amp;ldquo;sighting&amp;rdquo; events are to mean that the person has left the office, rather than the phone has gone to sleep.</description></item></channel></rss>