<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tesla on Will Schenk</title>
    <link>https://willschenk.com/tags/tesla/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tesla on Will Schenk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 21:48:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/tesla/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Short Term memory is a thing: forgetting as a creative act</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2017/why_short_term_memory_is_a_thing_forgetting_as_a_creative_act/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 21:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2017/why_short_term_memory_is_a_thing_forgetting_as_a_creative_act/</guid>
      <description>Our new app TezLab pulls in data from your phone and your car to show you how to use your car better. It helps you understand your driving habits, how you use your battery, and shows you what other drivers are up to. In order to do this, we need fairly sophisticated ways of understanding the world.
 Here, again, the role of the active faculty of forgetfulness, a kind of guardian, a supervisor responsible for maintaining the psychic, tranquility label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes, No, Maybe, Don&#39;t Know, WTF</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2016/yes-no-maybe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2016/yes-no-maybe/</guid>
      <description>Boolean logic is the basis for how computers work — digital means ones and zeroes, and ones and zeros is another way of saying boolean logic. In this world things are either true or they are false, there is no maybe, no hesitant pause,no anxiety provoking second thoughts. This type of logic goes back to Aristotle with the “law of the excluded middle”. Here’s wikipedia weighing in:
 In logic, the law of excluded middle (or the principle of excluded middle) is the third of the three classic laws of thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Owning a Tesla in Brooklyn</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2016/owning-a-tesla-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2016/owning-a-tesla-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>I’ve owned a Tesla in Brooklyn for about 10 months now. This is what I’ve learned so far. A Tesla in Brooklyn isn’t that hard.
I park my car on the street and have no regular place to plug in the car. This is very much like having a cell phone that you can only charge at the office or in coffee shops — kind of weird, takes a little bit of planning, but it can work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>