<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bots on Will Schenk</title>
    <link>https://willschenk.com/tags/bots/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bots on Will Schenk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/bots/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripting Twitter: Collecting Data and Writing Bots</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/scripting-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/scripting-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Lets build on our command line url exploring tool to look at how we can interact with Twitter. We are going to cover how to make a script that will pull information out of twitter, how to deal with its rate limiting, and how to interact with users on Twitter itself.
Twitter uses OAuth 1.0A as a way to authenticate requests. As a script writer, this is super annoying, because you can&amp;rsquo;t just stick a username and password in the environment and go from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bot Design Patterns</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/bot-design-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/bot-design-patterns/</guid>
      <description>In the antediluvian days before Google found everything for us, personal software agents were going to continuously do our bidding in cyberspace, tracking down air fares, making stock trades and otherwise doing futuristic things that we soon wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to live without. The anxiety of Y2K rose and crested, and the messianic aura of agents was washed away by more centralized and effective solutions.
The aspirational residue did yield some nuggets, and the idea has found partial success in the form of the bot.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>