<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on Will Schenk</title>
    <link>https://willschenk.com/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on Will Schenk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/docker/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging disposability for exploration</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/leveraging_disposability_for_exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/leveraging_disposability_for_exploration/</guid>
      <description>I play around with a lot of technology to see what&amp;rsquo;s out there and keep myself current with beginner techniques. One of the issues is that this can leave lots of stuff laying which can be messy. Here are some techniques I use to keep things under control.
There are two complementary principle&amp;rsquo;s that I focus on. One is reproducibility, and the other is disposibility. I want to be able to easily recreate what I was working on so that I don&amp;rsquo;t care if I throw it away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up an IPFS Node</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/setting_up_an_ipfs_node/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/setting_up_an_ipfs_node/</guid>
      <description>IPFS nodes that run in the broswer communicate over websockets to the main network. Lets walk through how to setup a IPFS server that your browser code can connect to in addition to the public gateways. Strategy     Wire everything up with docker-compose    Create and configure an ipfs container    Setup nginx with dummy certificate    Replace that certificate with certbot    Setup certbot to auto renew the certificates   Requirements   You will need:    A server with a domain or subdomain to use certbot to get a certificate    A working docker-compose install    I&amp;#39;m using a prebuilt docker image on Digital Ocean but the key part is to get the domain name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing guix on IntelNUC</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/installing_guix_on_nuc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/installing_guix_on_nuc/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting into Guix and Emacs lately, going back to my Free Software roots. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing. Guix is a functional package manager that you can use on top of a linux distribution to have repeatable and rollbackable builds. Guix System is a distrubution that&amp;rsquo;s Guix all the way down.
I have an Intel NUC lying around that I wanted to use, so this is my effort to get a working Guix System installation on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a slimmer go Docker container</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/building_a_slimmer_go_docker_container/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/building_a_slimmer_go_docker_container/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Go binaries are self contained, which means that they don&amp;rsquo;t need anything special installed in the environment to deploy them.  When people make &lt;code&gt;Dockerfiles&lt;/code&gt; to build go projects, they often include the the golang compilers and build tools, which isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary for running the container.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/somarat/healer&#34;&gt;healer&lt;/a&gt; Docker container that &amp;ldquo;Automatically heal docker containers that report themselves unhealthy&amp;rdquo; as an example of reducing the image size from 648MB to 17MB.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a chromebook for development</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/setting_up_chromebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/setting_up_chromebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just switch my pixelbook back to the stable channel, and this is what I did to get back to developing on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>