<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>emacs, on Will Schenk</title><link>https://willschenk.com/tags/emacs/</link><description>Recent content in emacs, on Will Schenk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/emacs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up emacs for typescript development</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2021/setting_up_emacs_for_typescript_development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2021/setting_up_emacs_for_typescript_development/</guid><description>I&amp;#39;ve been playing with deno and typescript, so I thought I&amp;#39;d document how to setup a basic tide environment with emacs. Prerecs Things will go better if you have nativejson support in your emacs build. I build from scratch which is super easy, but to check what you have you can run the following elisp: (if (functionp &amp;#39;json-serialize) (message &amp;#34;Native JSON is available&amp;#34;) (message &amp;#34;Native JSON is *not* available&amp;#34;)) Native JSON is available You also will need Node &amp;gt; 0.</description></item><item><title>Emacs Blog Writing and Navigation Mode</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2021/emacs_blogging_mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2021/emacs_blogging_mode/</guid><description>This blog is basically my labnotes where I explore different parts of technology. Almost all of my coding related activity starts off in this repo, while I explore different things to see how they work. I have a lot of things in drafts, and I wanted to learn how to build a simple emacs interface to let me navigate around my file system. I couldn&amp;#39;t find any good documentation on how to do anything with tabulated-list-mode so I spend the evening poking around and seeing how it works.</description></item><item><title>Installing emacs on buster</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2021/installing_emacs_on_buster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2021/installing_emacs_on_buster/</guid><description>I&amp;#39;ve already written about installing emacs-snapshot on debian buster, here are two additional ways. The first is to use flatpak, and the other is to build from source. Flatpack sudo apt-get install flatpak sudo apt install gnome-software-plugin-flatpak sudo flatpak remote-add --if-not-exists flathub https://flathub.org/repo/flathub.flatpakrepo Then: sudo flatpak install flathub org.gnu.emacs And running it: flatpak run org.gnu.emacs You can then pin it in your dock and you are good to go.</description></item><item><title>Getting Websters</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/getting_websters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/getting_websters/</guid><description>A few years ago I read a great post about the value of a good dictionary, which I installed on my laptop and then promptly forgot about. The post is very moving, and I recommend checking it out. It was recently mentioned on the planet emacs blog circuit and so I thought I&amp;#39;d document how to get it up and running on my laptop. Also I don&amp;#39;t understand what the appeal of John McPhee&amp;#39;s writing, I&amp;#39;ve tried a few of his books but found them all so plodding.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading emacs on debian</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/upgrading_emacs_on_debian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/upgrading_emacs_on_debian/</guid><description>Been playing with elfeed on Emacs 26.1 on buster and it keeps crashing. I think for font related reasons. So lets follow the Emacs Wiki Instructions to upgrade to emacs-snapshots and see if that helps. Add the snap shot repository. Make sure you have the tools installed so that apt can do it&amp;#39;s internet thing. sudo apt-get install software-properties-common sudo apt-get update Add the signing key: wget -q http://emacs.</description></item><item><title>Beginning Emacs</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/beginning_emacs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/beginning_emacs/</guid><description>Intro I&amp;#39;ve been dipping back ito the world of free software, and have been having a huge amount of fun getting back into emacs. I&amp;#39;m using it more of an operating system than I ever did before, as a way to navigate the world using a text interface. I&amp;#39;d never thought I&amp;#39;d be done with the terminal, but this is the first time that I&amp;#39;ve got something better and more powerful.</description></item><item><title>Emacs Tramp tricks</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/tramp_tricks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/tramp_tricks/</guid><description>Emacs is amazing. It&amp;rsquo;s a very different sort of thing than a code text editor like Vim or an IDE like VSCode. It&amp;rsquo;s a different way of thinking of how to interact with a computer, where you build up techniques on top of simple tricks that let you get amazing things done. Of course, part of the appeal/challenge is that you need to figure out how to make it work yourself.</description></item><item><title>Using Org Mode in Hugo</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/using_org_mode_in_hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/using_org_mode_in_hugo/</guid><description>I&amp;#39;m learning org-mode and I don&amp;#39;t really know what I&amp;#39;m doing, but this is how I&amp;#39;m trying out writing hugo posts with it. I&amp;#39;m used to markdown, so this is a what&amp;#39;s different post. Some minor org-mode tweaks For some reason when org-mode starts it doesn&amp;#39;t softwrap the paragragh text. I like to have it soft-wrapped so everything is on the screen if it&amp;#39;s not collapsed. Also having some nice indentation makes things visually cleaner, so add this snippet to your ~/.</description></item></channel></rss>