<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>emacs, on Will Schenk</title>
    <link>https://willschenk.com/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emacs, on Will Schenk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/emacs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading emacs on debian</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/upgrading_emacs_on_debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/upgrading_emacs_on_debian/</guid>
      <description>Been playing with elfeed on Emacs 26.1 on buster and it keeps crashing. I think for font related reasons. So lets follow the Emacs Wiki Instructions to upgrade to emacs-snapshots and see if that helps. Add the snap shot repository.   Make sure you have the tools installed so that apt can do it&amp;#39;s internet thing. sudo apt-get install software-properties-common sudo apt-get update   Add the signing key: wget -q http://emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning Emacs</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/beginning_emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/beginning_emacs/</guid>
      <description>Intro   I&amp;#39;ve been dipping back ito the world of free software, and have been having a huge amount of fun getting back into emacs. I&amp;#39;m using it more of an operating system than I ever did before, as a way to navigate the world using a text interface. I&amp;#39;d never thought I&amp;#39;d be done with the terminal, but this is the first time that I&amp;#39;ve got something better and more powerful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Tramp tricks</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/tramp_tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2020/tramp_tricks/</guid>
      <description>Emacs is amazing. It&amp;rsquo;s a very different sort of thing than a code text editor like Vim or an IDE like VSCode. It&amp;rsquo;s a different way of thinking of how to interact with a computer, where you build up techniques on top of simple tricks that let you get amazing things done. Of course, part of the appeal/challenge is that you need to figure out how to make it work yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Org Mode in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/using_org_mode_in_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/using_org_mode_in_hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#39;m learning org-mode and I don&amp;#39;t really know what I&amp;#39;m doing, but this is how I&amp;#39;m trying out writing hugo posts with it. I&amp;#39;m used to markdown, so this is a what&amp;#39;s different post. Some minor org-mode tweaks   For some reason when org-mode starts it doesn&amp;#39;t softwrap the paragragh text. I like to have it soft-wrapped so everything is on the screen if it&amp;#39;s not collapsed. Also having some nice indentation makes things visually cleaner, so add this snippet to your ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>