<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>socialinvestigator on Will Schenk</title>
    <link>https://willschenk.com/tags/socialinvestigator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in socialinvestigator on Will Schenk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/socialinvestigator/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling data out of Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/pulling-data-out-of-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/pulling-data-out-of-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>I like staring at the real time stats of Google Analytics. As a dashboard, it&amp;rsquo;s not really as amazing as Chartbeat is, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you drill down into the data as much as Mixpanel. But GA is super simple to setup and it&amp;rsquo;s Google, so everyone uses it.
Another obsessive/fun thing to do is to see where that spike in inbound traffic is coming from. On HappyFunCorp there are days where we get a sudden influx of Happy Thoughts which warms our hearts and floods our inboxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripting Twitter: Collecting Data and Writing Bots</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/scripting-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/scripting-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Lets build on our command line url exploring tool to look at how we can interact with Twitter. We are going to cover how to make a script that will pull information out of twitter, how to deal with its rate limiting, and how to interact with users on Twitter itself.
Twitter uses OAuth 1.0A as a way to authenticate requests. As a script writer, this is super annoying, because you can&amp;rsquo;t just stick a username and password in the environment and go from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal information from only a URL</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/personal-information-from-only-a-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/personal-information-from-only-a-url/</guid>
      <description>Ever wonder what you can find out by looking at a url? How about physical addresses, server location, emails, phone numbers, various links to other profiles (which can in turn be structurally scraped), technology stack, and more.
$ socialinvestigator net page http://willschenk.com/bio domain: willschenk.com created_on: 2014-10-31 expires_on: 2015-10-31 updated_on: 2014-10-31 registrar_name: ENOM, INC. registrar_url: www.enom.com registrant_contact: name: WILL SCHENK organization: HAPPYFUNCORP address: 18 BRIDGE STREET, 2E city: BROOKLYN zip: 11201 state: NY country_code: US phone: +91.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a command line utility with gems and thor</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/making-a-command-line-utility-with-gems-and-thor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/making-a-command-line-utility-with-gems-and-thor/</guid>
      <description>Some scripts work well because they are self contained and don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of dependancies, like the hosts on your network tracker.
Others scripts
 have more code than fits into a single file multiple options and switches have an extensive set of dependancies  And on those cases, its better to make a gem and use thor
Hammer of the Gods Lets figure out how to make some command line tools and package them up so that they can be shared and used by other people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>