<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>osx on Will Schenk</title>
    <link>https://willschenk.com/tags/osx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in osx on Will Schenk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/osx/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Setup Script</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/computer_setup_script/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/computer_setup_script/</guid>
      <description>Putting things in scripts makes it easy to get up and running quickly. Devops isn&amp;rsquo;t just for servers or Dockerfiles, you can also use it for your own environment. This is the script that I use to get my Chromebooks up and running after a wipe and how I get a new Linux machine up an running. Lets use the bash boilerplate to write our script.
I&amp;rsquo;ll update this later to include OSX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSX Script for Kiosk Mode</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2015/osx-script-for-kiosk-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2015/osx-script-for-kiosk-mode/</guid>
      <description>In the office, we run Jenkins on the same machine that we run Benevolent Gaze. During iOS builds, the iOS simulator will take over the screen for the build, and then leave the beautiful screen on the desktop, hiding our smiling faces. We want to return to Safari in this case, but we also want to make sure that if someone is actually in front of the machine it will let them do their thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Yosemite Faster</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/making-yosemite-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2014/making-yosemite-faster/</guid>
      <description>Since I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded to Yosemite my computer has gotten slower and slower. When it first boots up, it is it&amp;rsquo;s old fast self, but after a few hours everything slows down. Remember the days when you needed to restart your computer to keep it working well? I had forgotten, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really into remembering it.
I also upgraded to Airmail 2. I get a ton of email and it used it be a lot faster than using Mail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>