<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on Will Schenk</title>
    <link>https://willschenk.com/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on Will Schenk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/javascript/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapping a react app</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/bootstrapping_a_react_app_with_bootstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/bootstrapping_a_react_app_with_bootstrap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recipe for getting a blank react project with bootstrap up and running.  We&amp;rsquo;ll walk
though all of the steps that you&amp;rsquo;ll need to get a basic bootstrap based framework up and running,
ready for theming and component implementation using redux.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Manipulation in Firebase</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2018/image_manipulation_in_firebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2018/image_manipulation_in_firebase/</guid>
      <description>We can manipulate images using JavaScript directly, which can be run both on the server or browser environment. Lets take a look at how we&amp;rsquo;d do this using create-react-app and firebase. We will deploy a function on firebase that will download the user&amp;rsquo;s avatar, manipulate the image and overlay it with a mask, and then spit out an image.
Project Setup First make sure that you have nvm installed. We&amp;rsquo;ll need a different version of node for create-react-app then we will for firebase functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bower with Rails</title>
      <link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2015/bower-with-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2015/bower-with-rails/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s look at how we can integrate bower with rails and Sprockets. Bower is one of the two major javascript package managers, the other being the Node Package Manager, or npm. The biggest difference between the two is how the javascript is packaged up. Bower is the more straightforward of the two, and it mainly a way to distribute javascript and keep things up to date.
Install Bower The first step is to install bower.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>