<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chromebook on Will Schenk</title><link>https://willschenk.com/tags/chromebook/</link><description>Recent content in chromebook on Will Schenk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://willschenk.com/tags/chromebook/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Computer Setup Script</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/computer_setup_script/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/computer_setup_script/</guid><description>Putting things in scripts makes it easy to get up and running quickly. Devops isn&amp;rsquo;t just for servers or Dockerfiles, you can also use it for your own environment. This is the script that I use to get my Chromebooks up and running after a wipe and how I get a new Linux machine up an running. Lets use the bash boilerplate to write our script.
I&amp;rsquo;ll update this later to include OSX.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a chromebook for development</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/setting_up_chromebook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/setting_up_chromebook/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just switch my pixelbook back to the stable channel, and this is what I did to get back to developing on it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting up IPFS on a chromebook</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/setting_up_ipfs_on_chromebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2019/setting_up_ipfs_on_chromebook/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lets look at how to run an ipfs node on a chromebook. We are using the linux container for this, and in order to get the experience right we&amp;rsquo;ll need to install some chrome extensions to make it work seamlessly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Living with a Chromebook</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2017/living_with_a_chromebook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 12:37:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2017/living_with_a_chromebook/</guid><description>My experiment with the Chromebook has continued longer than I really expected. This machine is fun! Everything is so much faster and less cluttered, and I’m able to focus more.
This machine is something in between a laptop and a cellphone. Like a cellphone, it starts quickly, so dipping in and out is easy. Its just easy to grab the Chromebook to check something real quick, send out an email, whatever in the same way that unlocking your phone is easy.</description></item><item><title>Getting firebase and grpc working under termux</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2017/getting_firebase_and_grpc_working_under_termux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 17:36:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2017/getting_firebase_and_grpc_working_under_termux/</guid><description>firebase depends on grpc, which isn’t set to build right on the Chromebook. This is because node-pre-gyp, which is used to download precompiled binaries, is not setup correctly. In then uses node-gyp to compile the C++ bindings directly, which is also not setup correctly.
We are going to adjust the settings of node-gyp to make it compile things right under termux, and then we are going to tweak the grpc package itself in our local cache to make it build correctly.</description></item><item><title>More lessons learned working on a Chromebook</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2017/more_lessons_learned_working_on_a_chromebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 15:05:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2017/more_lessons_learned_working_on_a_chromebook/</guid><description>The Pixelbook just feels exciting in my lap, so much lighter and zippier than my MacBookPro. The one that I can’t quite bring myself to upgrade. Lets continue down the path of setting up this machine as a dev environment and see how well we can make it work.
First I should recognize my indebtedness to Kenneth White, who wrote up a great guide to setting up a secure Chromebook environment.</description></item><item><title>Writing code on a chromebook</title><link>https://willschenk.com/articles/2017/writing_code_on_a_chromebook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 17:12:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://willschenk.com/articles/2017/writing_code_on_a_chromebook/</guid><description>I’ve been disappointed with the latest round of MacBooks and it got me wondering what else it out there. (On the phone side the lack of head phone jack have made me jump ship to Android, which has been liberating.)
Chromebooks are pretty cheap and are super easy to use. I’m writing this on a Asus C100P. It’s small, has a touch screen, and folds into a tablet. There’s no backups to do, no security issues, it turns on immediately and there’s basically nothing to do to keep it working.</description></item></channel></rss>